<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>club.geekfun.sqlkit</id>
  <name>SqlKit</name>
  <summary>Agentic SQL database client for PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle, SQLite and more</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>Apache-2.0</project_license>
  <developer id="club.geekfun">
    <name>geek-fun</name>
  </developer>
  <url type="homepage">https://www.geekfun.club/products/sqlkit/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/geek-fun/sqlkit/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/geek-fun/sqlkit</url>
  <description>
    <p>This is a community package of SqlKit, maintained independently. It repackages the official upstream build unmodified.</p>
    <p>SqlKit is a cross-platform desktop SQL client built on Tauri. Alongside the usual editor and data grid it works as an agent: describe what you need in natural language and it writes queries, inspects schemas and returns results.</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Supports PostgreSQL, MySQL, MariaDB, Oracle, SQL Server, SQLite, DuckDB, ClickHouse, Snowflake, BigQuery and many more</li>
      <li>SQL editor with schema browsing, query history and saved queries</li>
      <li>Data grid with filtering and in-cell editing; import and export via CSV, Excel, JSONL and SQL</li>
      <li>Bring-your-own-key AI providers, including local Ollama</li>
    </ul>
    <p>This package talks to databases over the network. Its own connection store lives in its private per-app directory. JDBC-backed databases (Oracle, DB2, Teradata, Hive and others) need a Java runtime and driver jars, which SqlKit downloads into ~/.sqlkit; that directory is shared with the host so the download survives restarts.</p>
    <p>A few capabilities are not granted by default; enable the ones you need with "flatpak override":</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Keep a local SQLite/DuckDB file or .sql script accessible across restarts (files picked through the file-chooser dialog work without this, but the grant is per-pick): <code>flatpak override --user --filesystem=/path/to/db club.geekfun.sqlkit</code></li>
      <li>Reuse your existing host SSH keys for the SSH-tunnel feature: <code>flatpak override --user --filesystem=~/.ssh:ro club.geekfun.sqlkit</code></li>
    </ul>
    <p>SqlKit's built-in self-updater cannot replace a Flatpak install. New upstream releases are picked up by FlatPark and delivered through "flatpak update" instead.</p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">club.geekfun.sqlkit.desktop</launchable>
  <categories>
    <category>Development</category>
    <category>Database</category>
  </categories>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>database</keyword>
    <keyword>sql</keyword>
    <keyword>mysql</keyword>
    <keyword>postgresql</keyword>
    <keyword>oracle</keyword>
    <keyword>sqlite</keyword>
    <keyword>client</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <recommends>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
  </recommends>
  <provides>
    <binary>sqlkit</binary>
  </provides>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Querying a database in the SqlKit workspace</caption>
      <image>https://www.geekfun.club/sqlkit-client-ui.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.7.7" date="2026-07-23" />
    <release version="0.7.5" date="2026-07-23" />
    <release version="0.7.4" date="2026-06-30" />
    <release version="0.7.3" date="2026-06-30" />
    <release version="0.7.2" date="2026-06-20" />
    <release version="0.7.1" date="2026-06-19" />
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2026-06-19" />
    <release version="0.6.5" date="2026-06-17" />
    <release version="0.6.4" date="2026-06-17" />
    <release version="0.6.3" date="2026-06-17" />
    <release version="0.6.2" date="2026-06-17" />
    <release version="0.6.1" date="2026-06-16" />
    <release version="0.6.0" date="2026-06-16" />
  </releases>
</component>
