<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>net.huangyuhui.hmcl</id>
  <name>HMCL</name>
  <summary>Multi-functional, cross-platform Minecraft launcher</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <developer id="net.huangyuhui">
    <name>HMCL Team</name>
  </developer>
  <url type="homepage">https://hmcl.huangyuhui.net</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/HMCL-dev/HMCL/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/HMCL-dev/HMCL</url>
  <description>
    <p>This is a community package of HMCL (Hello Minecraft! Launcher), maintained independently and unaffiliated with Mojang or Microsoft.</p>
    <p>HMCL is a popular, cross-platform Minecraft launcher: it installs and manages game versions, mod loaders (Forge, NeoForge, Fabric, Quilt, LiteLoader, OptiFine), modpacks, mods and resource packs, supports Microsoft and offline accounts, and handles Java automatically.</p>
    <p>How this package works: a self-contained Java runtime is bundled to run the launcher. On first launch HMCL downloads the JavaFX UI components and, when you install a game version, the matching Minecraft Java runtime — so the first run needs a network connection. Everything HMCL downloads, plus your games and configuration, stays inside the sandbox under your home directory.</p>
    <p>By default the game directory lives in the sandbox (~/.local/share/hmcl). To use a Minecraft directory you keep elsewhere, enable the optional capability with "flatpak override":</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Use an existing game directory anywhere under your home: <code>flatpak override --user --filesystem=home net.huangyuhui.hmcl</code></li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Installing a Minecraft version with mod loaders</caption>
      <image>https://hmcl.huangyuhui.net/assets/img/installer_page.webp</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Personalization and appearance settings</caption>
      <image>https://hmcl.huangyuhui.net/assets/img/personalization_page.webp</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">net.huangyuhui.hmcl.desktop</launchable>
  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
  </categories>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>minecraft</keyword>
    <keyword>launcher</keyword>
    <keyword>mc</keyword>
    <keyword>mod</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <recommends>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
  </recommends>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <provides>
    <binary>hmcl</binary>
  </provides>
  <releases>
    <release version="3.15.1" date="2026-06-09" />
    <release version="3.14.1" date="2026-05-15" />
  </releases>
</component>
