<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.stablyai.orca</id>
  <name>Orca</name>
  <summary>AI orchestrator for running coding agents side by side</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <developer id="com.stablyai">
    <name>stablyai</name>
  </developer>
  <url type="homepage">https://onorca.dev/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/stablyai/orca/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/stablyai/orca</url>
  <description>
    <p>This is a community package of Orca, maintained independently. It repackages the official upstream Linux build unmodified.</p>
    <p>Orca runs coding agents side by side in terminal panes and worktrees, tracks their status in one workspace, and integrates with GitHub, Linear, SSH hosts, and the Orca mobile companion.</p>
    <p>Permissions: by default this package grants display, network, notifications, secret storage, audio, and a host command bridge. At startup, Orca creates a runtime PATH directory for commands already installed on the host, including Git, GitHub CLI (<code>gh</code>), GitLab CLI (<code>glab</code>), Node/npm/npx, Codex, Claude Code, OpenCode, Cursor Agent, Gemini, and other user-installed CLIs. Each command forwards through Flatpak's host-spawn portal and runs on the host. FlatPark does not install or authenticate those tools; install the CLIs you want on the host and sign in there first. Commands can be visible through host-spawn's default PATH or through your login shell, including shell-managed toolchains such as mise. For GitHub features, install GitHub CLI on the host and run <code>gh auth login</code>; for GitLab features, install GitLab CLI on the host and run <code>glab auth login</code> before using them from Orca.</p>
    <p>A few broad capabilities are not granted by default; enable only the ones you need with "flatpak override":</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Open existing projects anywhere in your home directory: <code>flatpak override --user --filesystem=home com.stablyai.orca</code></li>
      <li>Reuse host SSH configuration and keys for Git/SSH workflows: <code>flatpak override --user --filesystem=~/.ssh:ro com.stablyai.orca</code></li>
      <li>Expose local devices for advanced computer-use workflows: <code>flatpak override --user --device=all com.stablyai.orca</code></li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Orca running agents in parallel worktrees</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stablyai/orca/main/docs/assets/readme-hero.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.stablyai.orca.desktop</launchable>
  <categories>
    <category>Development</category>
    <category>IDE</category>
  </categories>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>AI</keyword>
    <keyword>agents</keyword>
    <keyword>IDE</keyword>
    <keyword>terminal</keyword>
    <keyword>worktree</keyword>
    <keyword>Codex</keyword>
    <keyword>Claude</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <recommends>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
  </recommends>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <provides>
    <binary>orca</binary>
  </provides>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.4.139" date="2026-07-14" />
    <release version="1.4.137" date="2026-07-12" />
    <release version="1.4.135" date="2026-07-11" />
    <release version="1.4.132" date="2026-07-10" />
    <release version="1.4.129" date="2026-07-09" />
    <release version="1.4.128" date="2026-07-08" />
  </releases>
</component>
